<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentList>
	<content contentuid="ha074f65dge959g41a1g87f0gdbdeb00d3250" version="1">Totems</content>
		<content contentuid="hd102ce7eg2f50g49afgab5fg64f81005da2d" version="1">You learn to bind primal nature spirits into sacred Totems so that you may safely channel their mystical abilities.</content>
	<content contentuid="head093d0gfdf5g4021g8c5cgc1c1404bd826" version="1">Totem of the Bear</content>
		<content contentuid="hc09673d9g9fc0g47a7gbe9bgd10698d12fcd" version="1">You bind a minor bestial spirit that grants you the ferocity of a bear. As a bonus action, you can grow claws from your fingers. With your claws, your unarmed strikes deal magical slashing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier on hit. If you have two free hands, the d6 becomes a d8. You can use another bonus action to cause the claws to disappear.</content>
		<content contentuid="h89cb4477g880fg4bf3gbffbgf136be5c0d6e" version="1">Totem: Reveal Claws</content>
			<content contentuid="h7c9ec313gc50cg4037gb2dfgfd113654d985" version="1">You can bond with your Totem and grow claws from your fingers. With your claws, your unarmed strikes deal magical slashing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier on hit. If you have two free hands, the d6 becomes a d8.</content>
		<content contentuid="hf5628e37g6ed9g437eg8848gf9ba9e32c6a4" version="1">Totem: Retract Claws</content>
			<content contentuid="hefcde9e6g6f7dg4593g9cf8gfb95877f7c6e" version="1">You can retract your claws ending the effect.</content>
		<content contentuid="h3d71a0c3gfb3ag42ccg9ffbg1c59262fe3db" version="1">Totemic Swipe</content>
			<content contentuid="h02b59de9gbb8bg46b7g9739g643172a964b7" version="1">Strike out with your claws dealing [1] or dealing [2] instead if both of your hands are empty.</content>
	<content contentuid="h84bb8775gad9eg4d7agb883gda96ed5bc0da" version="1">Totem of the Crossroads</content>
		<content contentuid="h8d4f086ag2342g4a91g8c94g03851cd7b4c7" version="1">REQUIRES: Heart Sacred Focus&#xA;You bind a minor Fey spirit that allows you to converse with wild creatures in your own tongue. You are always under the effect of speak with animals while you are conscious.</content>
	<content contentuid="h8f0317fcg1397g4ca3g95d7gde7fc943d9fc" version="1">Totem of the Eagle</content>
		<content contentuid="h57cc15dfg83bbg4db4g89ffg8ea84783d234" version="1">You bind a minor bestial spirit that grants you the sight of an eagle. You gain proficiency in Perception, and you have advantage on Perception checks</content>
	<content contentuid="h563d3275g7bd4g4614gacfdg5e66dac5b705" version="1">Totem of the Earthquake</content>
		<content contentuid="hf9f543ddged30g4706g8db7gec0a24a34421" version="1">You bind a spirit of earth that grants you destructive power. Once per turn when you hit with a melee weapon attack, you can deal an additional 1d6 damage of your weapon's type. This damage bonus increases as you gain Shaman levels; at 5th level (1d8), 10th level (1d10), and 15th level (1d12).</content>
		<content contentuid="h07773db9g93a5g4135gb7b5gbc82a7c54659" version="1">Unleash a Spirit of Earth on your enemy dealing an additional [1] damage of your weapons type.</content>
	<content contentuid="hd1cc0d25g271dg41b2g931bg26650e821e43" version="1">Totem of the Harvest</content>
		<content contentuid="h0d43f4cag0f5bg4e2fg8234g6772fc9d8a94" version="1">REQUIRES: Soul Sacred Focus&#xA;You bind a minor spirit of wild growth and bounty. You learn the spell Goodberry which you can cast once per Short Rest without expending a spell slot.</content>
	<content contentuid="h557be28cg0a41g4593gba0cgf3308a986023" version="1">Totem of the Hound</content>
		<content contentuid="hb419bf25g6ebdg40a1g9bffg97273a02c0a9" version="1">You bind a minor bestial spirit that grants you the senses of a hound. You gain proficiency in Survival, and you have advantage on Survival checks</content>
	<content contentuid="hefb10318g5f0ag45a7g94d0gc7d0b0fb5a11" version="1">Totem of the Mountain</content>
		<content contentuid="habc18b5cgedf0g42b9gabceg9885f3dd02f3" version="1">REQUIRES: Body Sacred Focus&#xA;You bind a minor spirit of the earth that hardens your skin like that of solid rock. So long as you are not wearing any armor or wielding a shield, your Armor Class is equal to 13 + your Constitution modifier.</content>
	<content contentuid="h123b932fg2539g4091ga7a4g9487a5b01ee6" version="1">Totem of the Panther</content>
		<content contentuid="h4c7f888ag468bg4dd2g90a5g7490c9c000c0" version="1">You bind a minor bestial spirit that grants you the steps of a panther. You gain proficiency in Stealth, and you have advantage on Stealth checks</content>
	<content contentuid="hcd5a4345gd553g4297g84a3gfd50abe115f2" version="1">Totem of the Quagmire</content>
		<content contentuid="hf1aef0cfg2040g46d4g800cg122df5e6d518" version="1">REQUIRES: Mind Sacred Focus&#xA; You bind a minor spirit of darkness that guards your mind and laces your words. You gain proficiency in Deception and Intimidation.</content>
	<content contentuid="h48624958ga0d0g47eegb63bg0f27382521c6" version="1">Totem of the Rains</content>
		<content contentuid="h0f0acfcag7335g46d4gadd8gda46f757bb1c" version="1">You bind a minor spirit of water that washes poison away like rain. You gain resistance to acid and poison damage, and you have advantage on saving throws to resist being poisoned.</content>
	<content contentuid="hcb010643g9433g411cgabceg2e73de2216e1" version="1">Totem of Twilight</content>
		<content contentuid="haf1c947eg60d1g4259gbe2fg367905b38920" version="1">You bind a minor spirit of darkness that grants you enhanced sight in the shadows. You gain Darkvision to a range of [1]. At 5th level this becomes Devil's Sight, and you can see through magical darkness.</content>
	<content contentuid="h21286809g8debg45e9g81fcg4532adbddbf0" version="1">Totem of the Waves</content>
		<content contentuid="hdb40820cg3e23g4caaga0caga9ba4639f6a9" version="1">You bind a minor spirit of water that allows you to shift like the sea. Once per short Rest as a reaction when you take a critical hit, you can to turn it into a normal hit. When you reach 12th level in this class, you can use this reaction twice between each Short Rest.</content>
	<content contentuid="hddf178dag79eag48acg9224g1fcfacaaba18" version="1">Totem of the Whirlwind</content>
		<content contentuid="h8d51d231gf44dg48f3g862fg91825decc1b7" version="1">You bind a minor spirit of air that speeds your strikes. When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can use your reaction to make another attack against that target.</content>
		<content contentuid="h82af5a82g46fbg4564g8b2bg9510ee6bbbff" version="1">Whirlwind Slash</content>
	<content contentuid="hc204f3cag02c2g4e9cg9228gf72f3af0d4ee" version="1">Totem of the Winds</content>
		<content contentuid="h140418fegc2b9g45c3g9624gdcbec3286726" version="1">You bind a minor spirit of the air which lends speed to your steps with a gust of mighty wind. Your walking speed increases by [1]. This bonus to your speed increases as you gain Shaman levels; at 5th level ([2]), 10th level, ([3]), and finally at 15th level ([4]).</content>
	<content contentuid="hacff76e1g2ff9g4b8bgbeb9gac83543efc03" version="1">Totem of the Bloom</content>
		<content contentuid="hc1ab66dcg4203g4546gbfbcg2c625712df53" version="1">You bind a spirit of wild growth that enriches the land around you. Once per Long Rest you may cast Create Food and Water without expending a spell slot.</content>
	<content contentuid="h06ddb55fg7834g4cf8g99ecg3ae4838578ec" version="1">Totem of the Eruption</content>
		<content contentuid="h30960f2egb2c3g4f39gb62bg6d125ebfe6bc" version="1"> You bind an elemental spirit that lends you its destructive power. Once per turn, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one of your Primal Magic spell slots to deal additional cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage (your choice) to the target equal to 1d8 per Spell Slot level spent.</content>
		<content contentuid="h6c475c8dg6fd0g41c4g8b88g5ec386303bae" version="1">Totemic Eruption: Cold </content>
		<content contentuid="h21416c83gcbe6g4a29g8eaag025beb06db4a" version="1">Totemic Eruption: Fire </content>
		<content contentuid="h06186d62g64efg4171ga1c7g36b7567d210d" version="1">Totemic Eruption: Lightning</content>
		<content contentuid="h38267772g6462g4dd7gb9f0ga9998a7233dc" version="1">Totemic Eruption: Thunder</content>
		<content contentuid="h2c78433fg37cdg4ddfgb6d5g2f73407f311b" version="1">Unleash the wrath of your bound spirits dealing an additional [1].</content>
	<content contentuid="h5365d00ega1d6g423dgbea1g7bbd2d3d2ecf" version="1">Totem of Growth</content>
		<content contentuid="hd73ca0e1gb719g403bg8f86g956bcf928ea0" version="1">REQUIRES: Body Sacred Focus&#xA; You bind a spirit of wild growth that can temporarily increase your size. Once per Short Rest you may cast the 'Enlarge' version of Enlarge/Reduce on yourself as a bonus action, without expending a spell slot or concentrating.</content>
	<content contentuid="he9ac54a3g62c7g4ddbg8189g05e47b1da175" version="1">Totem of the Grave</content>
		<content contentuid="h0387f6f8g98a4g4a5fg80cag9b5ade37270f" version="1">You bind a spirit of undead power which you can summon to your service. You learn Animate Dead and can cast it with your Primal Magic Spell Slots.</content>
	<content contentuid="hda000c1fgcfa7g4156g8cb0gc71833b403f7" version="1">Totem of Light</content>
		<content contentuid="h11ffa9f2g332bg46a0gbab0g72280a9d5e49" version="1">You bind a spirit of radiance that restores your spirit when you aid others. When you cast a spell of 1st-level or higher that restores hit points to a creature other than yourself, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier. </content>
	<content contentuid="hd66f97b9g087cg4ccfga3afgeb949d6cd389" version="1">Totem of Mirth</content>
		<content contentuid="hd9020d67ga393g4bbag968cg7a90aa22ec04" version="1">REQUIRES: Heart Sacred Focus&#xA;You bind a spirit of revelry and life that grants you renewed vigor. Once per long rest, you can use a bonus action to grant yourself temporary hit points equal to your Shaman level.</content>
	<content contentuid="hef950eb7g5e22g41fag806fge6a0563c8897" version="1">Totem of the Mystic</content>
		<content contentuid="h2bd15106gf6e5g4ff2ga595geca59244f6ad" version="1">REQUIRES: Mind Sacred Focus&#xA; You bind a spirit of secret knowledge that grants you the ability to peer into the minds of others. You are permanently under the effects of Detect Thoughts.</content>
	<content contentuid="hb4c95854g2a92g4c8dg83cbgd2789c95175b" version="1">Totem of the Wild</content>
		<content contentuid="h8f29409dg4982g4017gbc91gb981127e4f3b" version="1"> You bind a bestial spirit which you can call to your aid. Once per Long Rest, you can cast Summon Beast at a level equal to your Primal Magic slots without expending a slot.</content>
	<content contentuid="h79e95ba0g649bg4e45gbfccg6b9b58b9025e" version="1">Totem of Wrath</content>
		<content contentuid="hd5cedd4bgce5fg4d10g869bgb8b5efb5cf23" version="1"> You bind a spirit of anger that increases your power. When a creature fails its saving throw against Totemic Assault, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the damage roll.</content>
	<content contentuid="h946200b3g29efg4716gaea9g9006964d2330" version="1">Totem of the Hunt</content>
		<content contentuid="hb7ec2c4egf368g4437g82b7gda49b0531cee" version="1">You bind a spirit of the Wild Hunt that enhances your ferocity. Once per turn, you can grant yourself advantage on an attack roll if your target is within 5 feet of one of your allies.</content>
	<content contentuid="he08126ccga24bg4303ga9f4g4939c9027010" version="1">Totem of the Dawn</content>
		<content contentuid="h811a362eg613fg4e40g95d5g2ed750cc8f46" version="1">You bind a spirit of radiance which you can shield creatures from death. Once per Long Rest, you can cast death ward on a creature of your choice, without expending a spell slot.</content>
	<content contentuid="h96be6576g81a8g465bg97f7g573b1b39287f" version="1">Totem of Midnight</content>
		<content contentuid="hb5291b99g7d21g4ca7g98ccg060d4915cab9" version="1">You bind a sinister spirit which you can call to you. Once per long rest, you may cast Summon Shadowspawn at the level of your Primal Magic slots, without expending a spell slot.</content>
	<content contentuid="h42a67bebg18dfg4106g9d6eg67dd48867ae4" version="1">Totem of the Sun</content>
		<content contentuid="hb380657fg5df7g4d5egabeeg513c356105d0" version="1"> You bind a spirit of radiance that allows you to succeed when all hope seems lost. Once per short rest, when you fail a saving throw, you can choose to re-roll, possibly turning a failure into a success.</content>
	<content contentuid="h22b7fddbg92adg4989g8f3cg98f32fc17b20" version="1">Totem of the Vine</content>
		<content contentuid="h74d89ea9g6a54g4edcgb870g55c81d31ed07" version="1">You bind a spirit of wild growth which lends you the power to restrain your foes. You can cast Ensnaring Strike at 1st-level, at will, without expending a spell slot.</content>
	<content contentuid="h35b9e325gc109g46bbg89c0ga20c550db613" version="1">Totem of Binding</content>
		<content contentuid="h0190ce5fg68a5g4da8gaa5dg2ff954d1e327" version="1"> You can quickly bind a spirit to regain some of your power. Once per long rest, you can use a Bonus Action to regain one of your expended Primal Magic spell slots.</content>
	<content contentuid="h89eec00dgfdd5g49f6gb577gf0f7e21bf738" version="1">Totem of the Eclipse</content>
		<content contentuid="hec650e1cg3ef9g4964gaad0g0d7c3cec0eec" version="1"> You bind a powerful spirit that grants you resistance to the arcane. You gain resistance to all damage from spells.</content>
	<content contentuid="h4a01d6b6g5c97g4fe6g8c8dgbe05f3879599" version="1">Totem of the Elements</content>
		<content contentuid="hf04fff9fgccb3g4c6cg8f08g09d5020816d2" version="1">You bind an elemental spirit which you can call to your aid. Once per Short Rest, you can cast Summon Elemental without expending a Spell Slot.</content>
	<content contentuid="hcffbba4eg347fg4c3egbe4dg551ac496ac05" version="1">Totem of the Sapling</content>
		<content contentuid="he26fdd94g4c1cg4fbcga20cgaf20b263cf9b" version="1"> You bind a powerful spirit of wild growth which blesses your body with wondrous regeneration. At the start of each of your turns, you regain hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier, so long as you have no more than half of your hit points left and are not downed.</content>
	<content contentuid="heb367924ge5a6g478cgaac5g63d6bb284006" version="1">Totem of the Skies</content>
		<content contentuid="h9d9b9e5cg35d1g4017g9a7eg01cd7b500104" version="1">You bind a powerful spirit of elemental air which propels you through the air. You can now fly at will using your movement speed.</content>

</contentList>